[Music]
Hello and welcome to our newest busy
center launch event 20125 release wave
1. In this session we will show you one
new feature related to
sustainability and this is enablement of
using sustainability accounts and values
of posting sustainability entries
through general journals.
Okay, let's remind you how we
started. Uh, actually sustainability
functionality is all only two waves.
This is third wave. We are delivering
new updates for sustainability. In first
wave we enabled uh to posting
sustainability entries only through
sustainability journal. Then based on
your feedback uh you asked to enable
using purchase documents. So we enabled
purchase invoice, purchase order, credit
memos in previous wave. So from previous
wave you could add any information about
sustainability directly in your purchase
documents. And now we continue to invest
in these new options how you can post
sustainability values again based on
your feedback. And what it means
sustainability ledger entries will not
uh be recorded only with these two types
of documents but also by general
journal. So now you can post your
general journals as usual and plus you
can add additional sustainability values
there and on the end you can get all
sustainability ledger entries. So you
can report all environmental impacted uh
reports. Okay. uh there's some
differentiation uh between these uh
options. So in sustainability journals
you have the most commodity. So you can
post all three gas emissions you can
plus add new functionality from this
wave related to water and waste
management and plus if you do not have
proper value. So if you do not have
exact uh emission you want to post you
can use formulas. So you can calculate
uh your final your total emissions using
different embedded formulas. With
purchase documents and general journal
you cannot use formulas. So you can post
only total emissions if you have this
information. So if you got from external
source uh for example on your invoice if
you already have emission you can easily
post but there is no any calculation
there. So you cannot use formulas and
plus in this moment you can post only
greenhouse gas emissions. So not water
and
waste. Okay. Uh explain a little bit in
details how you can use in general
journal. So there are few not limitation
but uh few direction a few directions
how you can use in general journal.
First, if you want to post
sustainability values in general
journals, you must use one of these
document types, invoice or create memo
and blank. Of course, you can use these
three options. For others, you cannot
post any emission directly from general
journal. Why? For example, when you are
posting payments, probably there is no
any emission related to your payments.
So, emissions are coming related to your
invoices, your credit memos. This is
where we have emissions. So you can post
emissions only with these type of
documents. Further what you can post as
I said three different gas emissions. So
you can post carbon, you can post methan
and nitrogen dioxide uh here as well. So
you can post these three different
emissions and all of them as a total
values and before you posting what is
must you must have amount regular amount
in general journal. So if you do not
have amount for posting to uh general
ledger entries, you cannot post only
emissions. If you have only emissions
without any financial values, you must
go to sustainability journal. So this is
an option if you have financial amounts
to add in the same entry uh
sustainability values as well. So now my
colleague Mita will show you how it look
like in the practice. Thanks Alexander.
Now let's go to the demo.
I will open general journal and we'll
create one invoice
line. Here we will choose GL account
that has default sustainability account.
So we can see that sustainability
account number is field here but it is
possible to change it.
We insert
amount and total
emissions. And once we fill all of
necessary fields, we can do
posting. Once we finish the posting, we
can go to posted general journals to
verify what is the result. And here we
can see that we have the new line
created that
has sustainability account that we
choose and total emissions that we
insert. When we go to find entries, we
can see that there is a new
sustainability ledger entry uh created
for our sustainability account that we
added on the line.
Uh let's move back to general journal
and I will show you one more example. If
we try to
create payment line in general journal
with jail account that has default
sustainability account set on itself we
will got the error. So it is possible to
create journal lines with sustainability
accounts only if our type document type
is blank invoice or credit map. Thank
you. That was all for this demo. Now I
will move to Alexander. Thank you
Melissa for showing us this demo. Now
you can see we are continue to invest to
make it easier for you to post all
sustainability related uh information,
sustainability related values. So we
want to make this business as usual
every time if you have combined
different uh information that you do not
need to switch to another type of
journals if you have. So this is what we
are planning to do. We will continue to
invest in these different uh ways how to
post sustainability values based on your
feedback. And now we can close this uh
session. Thank you for watching us and
again I would like to invite you to
watch another sustainability related
videos.